《太空堡垒卡拉狄加》 前情回顾
ADAMA: Previously on Battlestar Galactica.
-你想必是...李  -是的
- You must be... Lee - Yeah
能抢兄弟的女朋友  有两下子嘛
Girlfriend stealer for a brother. Nice!
从没抢他的女朋友
Never stole his girlfriend. Mmm-hmm.
拙劣的撒谎者  站在你面前
Thank you. Really bad liar right here.
发生一场严重的车祸
There's been a terrible accident.
你的姐妹们和你的父亲都丧生了
Your sisters and your father were all killed.
那么你呢  亲爱的?
How about you, love?
花在你身上的肯定更多  嗯?
Bet you charge a lot more than that, eh?
闭上你肮脏的嘴  别再这么恶心了
Shut your filthy mouth. Stop being so disgusting.
这是你的父亲  盖尤斯
This is your father, Gaius.
我给你父亲找了个新地方住
I found your father a new place to live.
我最后一次见到他的时候
The last time I saw him,
他看上去很快乐
he seemed happy.
赫拉！
HELO: Hera!
比尔  我又做那个梦了
Bill, I've been having that dream again.
如果躺在那儿的是我  那我算什么?
If that's me lying there, then what am I?
她从她自己的死尸上拽下来的这个
BALTAR: She took these from her own mortal remains.
这些狗牌上的血 百分之百地
The blood on these dog tags is a 100% proof-positive match
正确吻合了卡拉·瑟瑞丝
for one Kara Thrace.
而你觉得这些音符中 包含着些别的什么意思
And you think there's some kind of meaning in these musical notes?
我多半只是暗中摸索
I'm just groping, mostly,
寻找模式  想弄明白我身上发生了什么
looking for patterns, trying to see what comes to me.
她是个让人好奇的半人半机器物件
She's a half-human, half-machine object of curiosity
在她的遗传密码某处藏着
that holds the key to our continued existence
我们种族得以继续存在的关键
somewhere in her genetic code.
那我们就给她输液  让她准备好
So let's get a tube in her and get her ready.
根据我们从山姆那得到的坐标
STARBUCK: Based on the coordinates we got from Sam,
我们可以断定那个赛昂殖民地就位于此处
we have determined that the Cylon colony is located here.
殖民地在黑洞的引力范围内
The colony's bound within the gravity well of the black hole,
但刚好能维持稳定的轨道
but maintains a stable orbit.
这里就是我们唯一的停泊场所
This right here is our only parking spot.
近程射击范围内
ADAMA: Point-blank range.
只留下一条路进出
APOLLO: Leave only one way in and out,
要混进去就几乎不可能
then make it impossible to get past the gates.
我们开始干活吧
Let's get to work.
请大家听我说几句
Can I have your attention, please?
我打算召集志愿者去救赫拉这孩子
I'm going to be asking for volunteers in the rescue of the child Hera.
甲板上有条线
There is a line running down this deck.
志愿者  站到右舷这边
Volunteers, move to the starboard side!
其他所有人  到左舷
Everyone else to the port.
40?我在派康从来没花超过30的!
40? I've never paid more than 30 on Picon.
这儿不是派康
This ain't Picon.
好吧  你得逞了
All right, you got me there.
这儿不是派康  好吧  40
This ain't Picon. All right, 40.
给他好好秀一把!
Show him a good time.
我不想要贴身舞  明白么?
I don't want a lap dance, okay?
试试嘛! 你会喜欢的!
Try it! You'll like it.
40你拿去吧  反正花他的  谢谢
Keep the 40, he deserves it. Thank you.
那么  你要接下那工作吗?
So, are you gonna take the job or not?
也许我应该去做
Maybe I should just do it.
我有些碍于面子了
Letting my pride get in the way.
终于开口了
Now you're talking.
谁会在意呢?  这只是你生命中的一小时
I mean, who cares? It's one hour of your time,
然后你就能有全新的生活
and then you have a whole new life,
新生活里不用夜间值班  不用军事训练  不用管舰队政务
a life without midnight watches or drills or Fleet politics
还有视察之类的垃圾事
or the inspections or any of that crap.
生活!  你每晚都能来这儿!
Life! You could be here every night.
他不会每晚都来的
He won't be here every night.
能拽他来一次就不错了
Can hardly get him here once.
为退役干杯?
To retirement?
你说呢?
What do you say?
为退役干杯!
To retirement.
耶!  对咧!
ELLEN: Yeah! Yes!
如果你不参加政治讨论
If you don't participate in the political conversation,
就等于放弃了你的发言权
then you are giving up your voice.
你就放弃了在我们的
You're giving up your right to have a say
社会发展过程中的一个表决权
in the way that our society is run.
怎么了?
What?
你还真沉醉于这些鬼东西里了  是吗?
You've really bought into all that crap, haven't you?
当然  我为此骄傲
I do, proudly.
话说  你也应该这样  哦  是吗?
And so have you, by the way. Yeah. Really?
因为那正是这身制服所代表的  我们受训也是为了维护它
'Cause that's what the uniform stands for. It's what we train to defend.
哦  你不会吧  真的!
Oh, you didn't. It's true.
不  不  不  不  这好悲哀  真悲哀.
No, no, no, no. That's sad. That's sad. Yes!
很可爱  但很悲哀
It's cute, but it's sad.
让我猜猜  他又在谈论投票以及…
Let me guess, he's going on about voting
民主生活方式的重要性了吧
and its importance to a democratic way of life again.
这么说你有在听喽
So, you were listening.
你没告诉过我  你哥哥是个理想主义的幻想家
You didn't tell me that your brother's an idealistic dreamer.
幻想家   真悲哀  事实上  他不是
Dreamer? The sad truth is, he's not.
在那浪漫的外表下
Beneath that romantic exterior
隐藏着一颗愤世嫉俗的心
lies the heart of a true cynic.
是吗?  讨论在升级嘛  会很有意思的
Really? This is going to be fascinating. Things are looking up.
是啊  这是许多许多许多原因之一
Yeah, it's one of the many, many, many reasons
使得他和老爸再也不说话了
that him and Dad aren't on speaking terms anymore.
哦  家庭纠纷  我爱听
Oh, come on. Family angst and drama. I love it.
来吧  伙计们  让我们来揭开些旧伤疤
Come on, boys, let's open up some old wounds.
别  别这样  父亲相信制度
No, let's not. ZAK: Dad believes in the system,
相信这身制服  相信一些比他自己更伟大的东西
believes in the uniform, believes in something greater than himself.
纠正下  父亲相信他自己
Correction. Dad believes in himself,
他自己的制服  他的制度  他的生活方式
his uniform, his system, his way of life,
如果你不和他一起呆在那个微小的幻想里
and if you're not with him in that tiny little bubble,
他会当你从来没存在过
then you might as well not exist.
如果你这么恨他 为什么还追随他的脚步?
If you hate him so much, why'd you follow in his footsteps?
喔  说得好!
Touché.
STARBUCK:
军队供我上四年大学
Service gave me four years of college.
我服役四年作为回报
I gave the service four years in return.
就那样简单  看见没? 愤世嫉俗
Simple as that. See? A cynic.
根植在他曾满怀情感的空荡内心
Right through to that big empty space that used to hold his heart.
亲爱的  我觉得我开始喜欢你哥哥了
Honey, I think I'm starting to like your brother.
你一定是肖恩
ROSLIN: You must be Sean.
是  我肯定是了
Yeah, I must be.
我希望是
I hope so.
我来拿这些吧  很漂亮  谢谢你  不客气
I'll take these. They're beautiful. Thank you. You're welcome.
来点白葡萄酒吗?  好的
Do you like white wine? I do.
有点奇怪  是吗?
Kind of awkward, huh?
和没见过面的人约会
Blind date and all?
不  不完全是
No, it's not, really.
我只是...有种感觉  觉得我认识你
It's just that I have this feeling that I know you.
哦?  嗯哼
Oh? Mmm-hmm.
真的吗?  嗯
Really? Mmm-hmm.
给你  肖恩
There you go, Sean.
谢谢  不客气
Thank you. Welcome.
哦  等一下
So, wait a minute.
你是我的学生
You were one of my students.
是的  罪名成立
Yeah, guilty as charged.
我是说  玛西一提你的名字我就知道了
I mean, as soon as Marcy mentioned your name I knew,
但是我不想告诉她
but I didn't want to tell her.
你知道我大到足够做你的...
And you knew I was old enough to be your...
老师?是的
Teacher? Yeah.
但是我早些时候已经毕业了
But I graduated some time ago.
我该走吗?  我说你该走了吗?
Should I go? Did I say you should go?
我没说要你走
I didn't say you should go.
今夜刚刚开始  显然你也是  让我们看看会发生什么
The night's young. Apparently, so are you. Let's see what happens.
肖恩
Sean.
你不会那么做的
You wouldn't do it.
为了那些钱?  你还真说对了  我会去
For that kind of money? Gods damn right I would.
不  你不会的
No, you wouldn't.
看着我的眼睛  告诉你会去做
Look me in the eye and tell me that you'd do it,
说你会为一份平民文职而这么做
that you'd do it for a civilian desk job.
我想听你亲口说出来  说啊!
I want to hear it come out of your mouth. Say it!
我就他妈的知道
I frakking knew it.
好啊!
Yeah!
加油  士兵
APOLLO:Come on, soldier.
伙计们 我爱你们
I love you guys. Yeah.
因为你们是我的家人
You guys are my family.
哦  天哪.哦  天哪  哦哟
Oh, my Gods. Oh, my Gods. Come on.
我爱你  哥哥  加油  小子
I love you, brother. Come on, big boy.
抬腿  好  上来了
Legs. All right. In you go.
你想出来吗?  是的  谢谢
APOLLO: You want out? Yes. Please. Thank you.
呃  他...他酒量一向很差
Well, he never could hold his liquor.
不像他哥哥
Unlike his brother.
喂  我还站得稳
Hey, I'm still standing.
也就是说该来干几杯了
Which means it's time for shots.
没必要折磨自己  盖尤斯
There's no need to torture yourself, Gaius.
相信上帝为你安排的计划就行
Just trust in God's plan for you.
上帝为我安排的计划是什么呢?
What is God's plan for me?
恩  你现在正按计划走呢
Well, you're following it right now.
是吗?
Am I?
通过领导幸存的人类
By taking charge of mankind's remnants
引导他们走向终点
and guiding them to their end.
什么的终点?
End of what?
盖尤斯
PAULLA: Gaius.
我们准备好走了  就一会儿  保拉
We're ready to go. Five seconds, Paulla.
好   我只是...
Okay. I'm just...
我给伊莎留够了两轮疗程的注射剂
COTTLE: I'm leaving Ishay enough for two more rounds of injections.
那应该可以让你的病情再稳定48小时
That should keep you on your feet for another 48 hours.
两天  好  那应该够了
Two days. Okay. That should be enough.
你正在耗尽你最后一丝生命  你知道的吧?
You're using up the last little bit of life you got. You realize that, don't you
是的  你已经明确跟我讲过好几次了
Yes. You've made that clear to me several times.
嗯
Mmm.
好了  弄好了  完事了
Right. That's it. You're done.
谢谢  谢谢你
Thank you. Thank you.
够了
Enough.
谢谢你  医生
Thank you, Doctor.
我只是在做分内的事
I'm just doing my job.
不
No.
你所做的要比那个多的多  你照料着…
You've done much more than that. You've taken a patient who should've died
一个几年前就该死去的病人  你给了她一个机会
years ago, and you've given her a chance,
去抗击癌症  赛昂  还有她自己的倔强脾气
despite cancer and the Cylons and her own obstinate nature.
并且你给了我所剩下的那一点点时间
And you've given me the little time I have left,
为此  你让我对你...
and for that, you have my...
心存感激
My heartfelt gratitude
和谢意
and my thanks.
我不知道该说什么
Well, I don't know what to say.
不  不  别  别说什么
No, no, don't, don't.
别破坏你的形象  点根烟发你的牢骚去吧
Don't spoil your image. Just light a cigarette and go and grumble.
现在她是你的病人了  伊莎
She's your patient now, Ishay.
伊莎   我我眼睛看不太清楚
Ishay, I can barely see straight.
不足为奇
I'm not surprised.
注入了那么多药物 你都快能从床上飘下来了
You're so pumped full of drugs you could float off this bed.
好吧  两天?
Okay. Two days?
好吧   两天
All right, two days.
这个计划刚开始成形  但有一点是明确的
The plan's just starting to take shape, but one thing's clear.
像往常那样  猛禽机干最棘手的活
Raptors get the toughest job, as usual.
这会需要一些特殊的飞行技巧
This will require some special piloting skills, and I mean special,
像坐在过山车中把线穿进针眼那样特殊
threading a needle while you're on a rollercoaster special.
在这时候说这个有点多余了
While it seems a little redundant at this point,
上头说这个任务是自愿参加的  所以...
the word's come down that it's a volunteer assignment, so...
这才是我的猛禽牛仔们
That's my Raptor wranglers.
总是想找个新颖而又有趣的死法
Always looking for new and interesting ways to get killed.
我没有对你们说大话  伙计们  我们的情报不足
I'm not going to lie to you boys. We are thin on intel on this one.
但是赛昂们相信对卡维尔来说关那个小女孩
The Cylons believe that the most logical place for Cavil to have taken the girl
最合理的地方就是赛昂殖民地的最内部
is deep into the interior of the colony.
最可能的  就是这里
Best guess. Right here.
如果使用核武器  我们靠得太近了  导弹也一样
ADAMA: We'll be in too close for nukes. Same thing goes for missiles.
这将会是一场严格意义上的枪炮战
No, this is going to be strictly a gun battle.
就像冲在最前面的两条旧船  近距离射击范围里搏杀
Like two old ships on the line, slugging it out at point-blank range.
我要炮手们恪守岗位 做到立即开火
I want the gun captains to do their job and start firing immediately
并且持续作战直到弹药耗尽
and to continue to fire until they run out of ammo.
然后…  我要他们开始扔石头
Then, I want them to start throwing rocks.
只要我们跳跃到他们的视线里
They're gonna have every gun trained
他们会把所有的火力直接对准我们
directly on us as soon as we jump in.
如果我们要有所行动的话
If we have any shot at this,
我们就必须要侵入到他们的火力控制系统中去
we're gonna have to interrupt their fire control systems.
那山姆到底要怎样才能做到?
And just how the hell is Sam supposed to help with that?
如果我们能把他接入卡拉狄加的雷达
If we can plug him into Galactica's dradis,
超光速引擎和指挥 控制和通信系统中
FTL and C3 systems,
那么我们一旦跳跃过去  他的意识就能直接
his mind should then be able to directly communicate with the colony's Hybrids
和殖民地的混合体对话
once we jump in.
理论上说  他的意识应该还可以控制他们的指令
Theoretically, his mind should still be able to control their commands
并延迟他们的反应时间
and slow down their response time.
好吧
Okay.
我想  我们试试吧
Let's do it, I guess.
还是有个问题
There's a catch.
要把船上的这些系统设置硬件路由联接到
Routing hardware connections from all those systems all over the ship
这个房间里的话要花费几个星期的时间
into this room is gonna take weeks.
而我们如果只是把他接入到现有的线路中 会简便快捷得多
It's a lot easier, faster if we just move him to the existing lines.
那好  往哪接?
Okay, where's that?
最好的地方就是作战指挥中心了
Well, the best place is the CIC.
我要找一个我信得过  得到普遍尊重的人
ADAMA: I need someone to lead this Fleet
来领导这只舰队
who I trust and demands universal respect.
那么基地之星和整个舰队就交给你了
So the Baseship and the Fleet are yours.
谢谢你  长官  我不会让你失望的
Thank you, sir. I won't let you down.
我知道你不会
I know you won't.
到集合地再和你们相见
And I'll see you at the rendezvous.
如果我们在12小时内没有到达 那我们就不会再出现了
If we're not there in 12 hours, we won't be coming.
明白  长官
Yes, sir.
祝你顺利  长官
Good hunting, sir.
谢谢你  星上将
Thank you, Admiral Hoshi.
现在把他们都从减压舱里冲出去还不迟
Still not too late to flush them all out the airlock.
太花时间了
Take too much time.
我想这就是你所谓的善恶自有报
I suppose this is what you could call poetic justice.
或者说是顺其自然  总之
Or what goes around, comes around. Either way,
恭喜你  总统先生
congratulations, Mr. President.
谢谢你  阿达玛先生  祝你好运
Thank you, Mr. Adama, and the best of luck.
星上将  长官  长官
Admiral Hoshi, sir. Sir.
呃  我说的"长官"是…  没错  祝好运
The "sir" has... Right. Good luck.
你也是  长官
You too, sir.
殖民地总统  舰队上将司令官  离舰
President of the Colonies, Admiral of the Fleet, departing.
好了  最后一架猛禽离舰  伙计们!  最后一架猛禽离舰!
All right, last Raptor out, people, last Raptor out.
任何留下的人  你的小命就归我们了!
Anyone left behind, your ass belongs to us.
好极了  我们能把这个塞到那里吗?
Great. Can we tuck this in there?
听着  我不和你们一起走
Listen, I'm not coming with you.
盖尤斯  别这样  盖尤斯  我们的人民需要你  我主意已定
Gaius, please, Gaius, our people need you. I've made up my mind.
我不属于你们  保拉 我从未属于过你们
I don't belong to you, Paulla. I never belonged to you.
是你们霸占了我
You appropriated me.
对不起  如果我让你们认为...
I'm sorry. I'm sorry if I led you to believe...
现在他们都是你的了 保拉  好好享受
They're all yours now, Paulla. Enjoy them.
飞行员  你的乘客都齐了
Pilot, you have your passengers.
盖尤斯  不要这样
Gaius. Don't do this.
也许你我会来世再见
Maybe I'll see you in the next life.
博士
APOLLO: Doctor.
卡拉狄加  这里是基地之星实战指挥
MAN ON RADIO: Galactica. Baseship actual.
旗舰已经转移到基地之星
Flag has been transferred to the Baseship,
我们的蝮蛇战机已经准备接手执行舰队的护航任务
and our Vipers are ready to take over CAP duties for the Fleet.
收到  基地之星  护航由你舰执行
Roger that, Baseship. You have the CAP.
旅途平安  上天保佑卡拉狄加
Safe journey. Godspeed, Galactica.
让我们吹响号角
Let's go around the horn.
我是副长
This is the XO.
所有战斗岗位准备向我报告
All combat stations prepare to report.
超光速引擎   就绪
FTL. Go.
我们会在这里做好筛选  就照我的手术台那样做好准备
ISHAY: We'll set up triage here. Just prep the table the way that I do.
武器系统  就绪
TIGH: Weapons. MAN 1: Go.
战术系统   把伤员分开
Tactical. Separate out the wounded.
就绪   这边放我们救得活的  那边放我们救不活的
MAN 2: Go. Those we can save, and those we can't.
轮机室  就绪
Engineering. WOMAN 1: Go.
我怎么知道哪些救得活?
How will I know?
拿着记号笔
Take this marker.
损管控制  就绪
Damage control. MAN 3: Go.
在那些伤得太重的人的脑门上画个X
Put an "X" on the forehead of those who are too badly hurt,
等你看到他们你自然就知道了
and you'll know when you see them.
主排炮台  就绪
Main batteries. MAN 4: Go.
引擎室  就绪
Engine room. WOMAN 2: Go.
就到我们了
We're next.
医务室
Sick bay.
医务室就绪
Sick bay to go.
蝮蛇机编队  就绪
Viper wing. Go.
突击一队  就绪
Assault One. Go.
突击二队
Assault Two.
就绪
Go.
预备队
Reserve forces.
就绪
Go.
通讯一队  就绪
Com One. MAN 5: Go.
抱歉  卡布里卡
Sorry. BALTAR: Caprica.
通讯二队  就绪
Com Two. WOMAN 3: Go.
你在这干嘛?
What are you doing here?
我觉得你不应该待在这里
I don't think you should be here.
恐怕我经过的战斗比你要多
Probably been in more battles than you have.
观点合理  生命维持系统
Fair point. Life support.
应急系统待命
MAN 6: Emergency systems standing by.
是啊  我想更确切的问题是我在这干嘛呢?
Yeah, I suppose the more pertinent question is what am I doing here.
我到底在想什么?
What the hell was I thinking?
检查各甲板防爆门安全
Secure blast doors on all decks.
艾伦
Ellen.
我想我们这上面也就绪了
I think we're a go up here.
所有战位已报告就绪  长官
All stations report, sir.
给我接全舰
Connect me just to the ship.
我是上将
This is the Admiral.
为确保大家正确认识稍后的任务...
Just so there'll be no misunderstandings later,
卡拉狄加见证了不少的历史
Galactica's seen a lot of history,
经历了无数的战斗
gone through a lot of battles,
而这将会是她的最后一战
this will be her last.
只要我们不辜负她
She will not fail us
她就不会让我们失望
if we do not fail her.
如果我们顺利完成任务 卡拉狄加会带我们回家
If we succeed in our mission, Galactica will bring us home.
如果我们没有...
If we don't,
那也就无所谓了
it doesn't matter anyway.
各单位  行动
Action stations!
开始倒计时  倒计时开始
Start the clock. Start the clock.
听我口令  准备跳跃
Jump on my mark.
五  四  三  二  一  跳跃
Five, four, three, two, one. Mark.
我们承受不住太多的炮击
We can't take much of this.
时候到了  山姆
It's time, Sam.
凭汝亲眼瞭望
Look through the eye to know thyself.
殖民地混合体掉线了
ELLEN: The colony Hybrids are offline.
他们很快会发射突袭机的
They'll be launching Raiders any minute.
行动
Go.
派出所有编队
Launch all wings.
战机都已发射
Birds are away.
前进  极限速度!  三  二  一  冲撞!
All ahead, flank speed. Three, two, one. Hit it!
全员作好撞击预备
TIGH: All hands brace for impact.
突击一队  准备行动
Assault One, standby.
他们来了  干掉他们!
Here they come, let's take them!
照明
APOLLO: Light it up.
突击一队跟我来
Assault team, on me.
你们去侦查下 好吗
You guys scout me out, okay?
气压  我们测到气压了  长官  一个大气压
Pressure. We've got pressure, sir. One atmosphere.
突击一队  这里有气压
Assault One, we got pressure.
一队  摘掉头盔
Alpha Team, helmets off.
前进
Move out.
我想我们失去了筋斗
I think we lost Cartwheel.
雷达在这儿完全废掉了
Dradis is almost useless out here.
是啊  我希望他们的也一样  有他们发现我们潜入的迹象吗?
I hope that works both ways. Any sign they've spotted our approach?
我好一会没监视什么仪器了
I haven't looked at the instruments in a while.
我想你不会希望我现在去看的
I don't think you want me to start now.
最好别
Maybe not.
先把武器准备好  头骨  我们接近了
Let's go weapons hot, Skulls. We're getting close.
你确定吗?
You sure about that?
不  但我也不想从这该死的地方出去的时候没武器用
No, but I don't wanna come out of this crap with cold weapons, either.
核弹准备好了
Nukes are hot.
知道吗  这让我想起了以前着陆资格考试的时候
You know, this reminds me of that time back during...
三号炮台  重新定向火力!  右舷十度!
Battery Three, redirect your fire 10 degrees starboard.
集中火力拿下赛昂人的那些炮台!
Concentrate on taking out the Cylon batteries.
热狗和女士杀手
Hotdog and Ladykiller,
集中火力打掉来袭的赛昂突袭机  方位084 定向229
concentrate on taking out Cylon Raiders coming in at 084 count...
明白  卡拉狄加  我们看到他们了
All right, Galactica. We got them.
气闭舱已密封  开始切割
WOMAN ON RADIO: We have a hard seal. Go.
你就准备一直做测试
BOOMER: You're gonna just keep doing the tests?
即使殖民地陷落也充耳不闻?
Even with the colony coming down around your ears?
我想你高估了他们的成功几率
I think you overestimate their chances.
他们也许可以暂时迷惑我们的混合体
They may have confused our Hybrids temporarily,
但是我们火力占优  兵力占优
but we have superior firepower and superior numbers,
最终我们还是占绝对优势
and in the end, it's all about mathematics.
山姆!山姆  听我说
Sam. Sam, listen to me.
你花费了太多能量去突破自动控制系统
You're pushing too much energy through the ACS.
你最好撤出  应该改去攻击总线  听到了吗?
You gotta back off, or you're gonna blow the main bus, you hear me?
山姆!
Sam!
眼中隐有秘密  谜题之中蕴含答案
There are secrets within lies, answers within riddles.
放过自动控制系统?开玩笑  格伦
Lay off the ACS, you betcha, Galen.
开启心智  倾听本心  行结束
Open your mind and hear what your heart wants to deny. End of line.
你从来就不该相信她
You never should have trusted her.
与信任无关
Trust didn't enter into it.
我纯粹是漏算了她居然会做这种徒劳的事情
I simply miscalculated her need to engage in gestures of futility.
我们不得不假定她会试着去联络
We have to assume that she'll try to make contact
登上母舰的殖民地军队
with the Colonial forces aboard the colony.
是时候主动出击了
It's time to go on the offensive.
我们必须小心  火力太强可能会害了那个孩子
We must be cautious. Too much force could risk killing the child.
真的?你这么觉得?
Really? You think?
请继续陈述那些显而易见的东西
Please continue stating the perfectly obvious.
这我充满自信
It fills me with confidence.
我为你自豪
I'm proud of you.
什么?
What?
因为你这么做
For doing this.
在你能离开的时候留下来
For being here when you could've just walked away.
我知道我从没说过  但我一直都想要为你自豪
I don't think I ever said it before, but I always wanted to be proud of you.
我想这曾是我一直以来唯一的缺憾
Guess I always felt that was the only thing missing.
所有片断都变得有条不紊
NO. 6: All the pieces are falling into place.
你们将托起人类和赛昂共同的未来
You will hold the future of Cylons and humans in your hands.
我会?  我会?
I will? I will?
你能看得见他们? 你能看得见他们?
You see them? You see them?
给我重新接通!
Reconnect me!
赛昂刚在21层甲板上轰了个洞!
Cylons just blew a hole into Deck 21.
该死的赛昂武士们会整排地入侵!
Frakking Centurions will be pouring in at platoon strength.
跟着我  前进!
On me, let's move!
等等
Wait.
告诉老头子  这是我欠他的
Tell the old man I owed him one.
但也改变不了你做过的事
Doesn't change anything you did, though.
是的
No.
我们都做出自己的选择
We all make our choices.
今天我做出自己的选择
Today I made a choice.
我想这也是我的最后一个
I think it's my last one.
够了  这实在够"感人"的  我们能离开这鬼地方了吗?
All right, this is really touching. Can we get the hell out of here?
要知道你们的猛禽已经被摧毁了
You should know that your Raptor's been destroyed.
你们不能原路回去了
You can't go back that way.
是  不过我们的计划不是这样
Yeah, well, that's not the plan.
呃  能不能不告诉她我们的计划?
Can you not tell her the plan?
说得对
ATHENA: Right.
两天之内七次错过缓冲绳
TIGH: Missed the trap seven times in two days.
这可是卡拉狄加的新纪录
There's a new Galactica record.
教官说你被淘汰了  菜鸟
Regs say that you've washed out, Rook.
是时候考虑下转行了
Time to look for a new career.
您想让我怎么做  长官?
What do you want me to do, sir?
为了保住职位求您?  向您下跪?
Do you want me to beg for my billet? Do you want me to crawl?
我只想让你每次降落时别他妈老在我甲板上打洞
I want you to land your frakking bird without digging holes into my deck.
听上去怎样  啊?
How's that, huh?
做个称职的飞行员如何  一个配得上这套制服的军官
How about being a pilot, an officer worthy of the uniform?
把自己的工作当回事儿  不要让你的私人生活妨碍你
Take your job seriously. Don't let your personal life get in the way.
我看过你的简历  了解过你的生活
I've read your jacket, your whole story.
我知道你的家人都去世了  知道你无家可归
I know that your family's gone, and I know that you have no home.
军役就是你的全部  可它也正从你手中溜走
All you got is the service, and it's slowly slipping away.
这都是因为你为自己能幸存下来感到愧疚
All because you're all wrapped up in survivor's guilt,
你想方设法让自己精疲力竭
and you're trying to find a way to wash yourself out.
他是专家  让他检查下你的神经衰弱
The doctor's in. Check your neuroses at the door.
很多人死在这艘船上
A lot of people have died on this ship.
这里游荡着好多的鬼魂
There's a lot of ghosts running around here.
你不会想把他们带进你的驾驶舱
You don't want to pull them into your cockpit with you,
不然你就没法活着回来  你懂我的意思吗?
because you won't come back alive. Do you understand that?
是的  长官
Yes, sir.
我才不信呢  不过可能将来你会懂的
I don't think you do, but maybe someday you will.
至于现在...
For now,
明天要对上缓冲绳  菜鸟
make the trap tomorrow, Rook.
解散
Dismissed.
谢谢你  长官  我欠你的
Thank you, sir. I owe you one.
不光是你  很多人都欠我的
You and a lot of other people owe me one,
但你知道吗  很少有人真的知恩图报
but you know what, very few people ever pay back,
特别是那些欠我小命的
especially the ones that owe you their lives.
终有一天我会报答您的  长官  在某个非同寻常的时刻
I'll pay you back one day, sir, when it really means something.
你可记好了
You do that.
给这个人再做检查  帮我架一座大缸径的静脉注射仪
ISHAY: Okay, get this guy cross-checked and set me up a large-bore IV.
给这个士兵上纱布
I need a set of vitals on this Marine over here.
这里这个要做CT扫描  快把他给我弄出去!
I want a CT scan here on this one, and get him the frak out of here.
没事的  你不会有事的
ROSLIN: Here we go. It's all right. You're gonna be all right.
他没救了
He's a goner.
好的  你会...你会好起来的  没事了
All right, you'll be... You're gonna be all right. Okay.
怎么这么久?
What took you so long?
停下来喝了杯咖啡
Stopped for coffee.
还有其他猛禽队员抵达吗?
How many other Raptor teams made it?
没看见别人了
Haven't seen anybody else.
好吧  照来的路回去
Okay, back the way we came.
枪手  掉头  是  长官
Guns, point. MAN: Yes, sir.
我们原路返回
We're retracing our steps.
再说一次  阿波罗!
ADAMA: Say again, Apollo!
我收不到你上次的讯息!
I cannot copy your last transmission.
我是副长
This is the XO.
红条队去狙击登舰的敌人  21层甲板  左弦  10号区
Red stripes to repel boarders, Deck 21, portside, frame 10.
成功夺回目标!  重复  成功夺回目标!
APOLLO: We got the prize. Repeat, we have the prize.
与突击二队会合  正在返回基地
Formed up with Assault Two and are heading back to base.
收到!  预计五分钟  实战指挥完毕
Roger that. ETA five minutes. Actual out.
火!  这上面起火了!
Fire! We got a fire up here!
给我接指挥单位!  是  长官!
Connect me to Command Unit. MAN: Yes, sir!
出动预备力量守住减压舱!
Move reserve forces to guard airlock.
突击队正在路上  预计五分钟后抵达
Assault force is en route. ETA five minutes.
重复一遍  预计五分钟后抵达
I repeat. ETA five minutes.
我们是自己人!
APOLLO: We're friendly!
停火!自己人!
MAN: Hold your fire! Friendlies!
兰杰尔  彼得斯  归队!
Rangel, Peters, form up!
刚才不好意思
Sorry about that.
博士  干得不错  谢谢
Doc, you did good. BALTAR: Thank you.
我们带走赫拉  好的
We'll take Hera. Right.
快！
Come on.
快！带上赫拉
Come on. Bring Hera.
带他们离开这儿  带他们离开这儿
APOLLO: Get them out of here. Get them out of here.
退后  退后!
Fall back. Fall back!
天啊  赫拉
Oh, my Gods. Hera.
安全!
MAN: Clear.
天啊  检查他的状况
ATHENA: Gods. STARBUCK: Check his status.
扎紧带子 回来
Keep that belt tight on and get back here!
坚持住
ATHENA: Hang on.
赫拉!
Hera!
赫拉  回来这里!赫拉!
Hera! Come back here. Hera!
看着我!
HELO: Look at me.
去追  不  你会失血过多的
Go. No, you'll bleed out.
去啊!
Go!
快去!
没事了
Okay.
我没子弹了
I'm empty.
两枪
Two rounds.
赫拉!
Hera!
我以前来过这里
I've been here before.
是的
Yes.
我们应该是要...
We're supposed to...
进入歌剧院
Go into the opera house.
这个还活着!
MAN: This one's still alive.
赶快把他弄出去!
Get him the hell out of here!
他们带着孩子
They got the girl.
他们找到小女孩了!
They've got the little girl!
这样事情就简单多了
This makes it a lot easier.
我带上小女孩  然后就离开这里
I just take the little girl and I'm out of here.
想得美
Not a chance.
卡维尔  我们不会把赫拉交给你的  你知道的
Cavil, we won't let you take Hera. You know that.
我完全不这么想
I know nothing of the kind.
我倒觉得我会看你们尾随着
I know I'm going to watch you chase your tails across the universe
满宇宙地再追个四年
for another four years.
这绝不可能发生
TIGH: That's not gonna happen.
这东西是我的种族幸存下去的关键
This thing is the key to my people's survival,
得不到它我不会离开
and I'm not leaving without it.
赫拉不是什么物件  她是个孩子
Hera's not a thing. She's a child,
她也是人类幸存的关键
and she holds the key to humanity's survival, as well.
你怎么知道?
And how do you know that?
我能看到天使
I see angels,
天使就在这间屋子里
angels in this very room.
我也许是疯了  但那并不表明我就是错的
Now, I may be mad, but that doesn't mean that I'm not right.
因为这里还有另一种力量在起作用
Because there's another force at work here.
从来如此
There always has been.
这无可否认  我们全都体验过
It's undeniable. We've all experienced it.
这间屋子里的每个人都亲眼目睹了他们难以理解的事件
Everyone in this room has witnessed events that they can't fathom,
更别说给它提供一个合理的解释
let alone explain away by rational means.
在预言中被破解的谜题
Puzzles deciphered in prophecy.
少数人才能触到的梦境
Dreams given to a chosen few.
我们心爱的人逝去
Our loved ones, dead,
又重生
risen.
无论我们愿意把这叫作"神"或者"众神" 还是某种庄严的启示
Whether we want to call that God or Gods or some sublime inspiration
或神圣的力量  我们无从知晓无以理解
or a divine force that we can't know or understand,
这都不要紧...都不要紧
it doesn't matter. It doesn't matter.
它就在这里  它存在着
It's here. It exists,
在它力量的引导下  两方的命运交织在一起
and our two destinies are entwined in its force.
如果这是真的...我只是说"如果"
If that were true, and that's a big "if,"
我又怎么知道这种力量对我们有益?
how do I know this force has our best interests in mind?
你怎么知道神站在你们那边  博士?
How do you know that God is on your side, Doctor?
我不知道
I don't.
神不站在任何一边
God's not on any one side.
神是一种自然的力量  超越了善与恶
God's a force of nature, beyond good and evil.
善与恶是我们制造的
Good and evil, we created those.
你要打破循环?
You wanna break the cycle?
打破生  死  重生
Break the cycle of birth? Death? Rebirth?
毁灭  逃避  死亡的循环
Destruction? Escape? Death?
机会就在我们手中...
Well, that's in our hands,
而且只在我们手中
in our hands only.
这需要一个信仰的飞跃
It requires a leap of faith.
需要我们生活在希望
It requires that we live in hope,
而非恐惧中
not fear.
如果我放弃这个女孩  就意味着我们种族的灭绝
If I leave you this girl, that means the destruction of my people.
我们灭绝了  还怎么信仰
How does our extinction fit into this picture
你描述的蓝图?
that you want us to believe in?
我们会给你复活技术
We'll give you resurrection.
索尔!
Saul!
你给我们赫拉  我们就给你复活技术
You give us Hera and we will give you resurrection.
战争到此结束
But the war ends here.
不要再来侵扰人类...
You leave humanity in peace
从现在起永久地放弃追杀
and give up the pursuit now and for all time.
一言为定
Agreed.
我们怎么知道你是否守信?
How do we know we can take your word for it?
你们不知道
You don't.
你们需要有"信任上的飞跃"
You have to make a leap of faith.
你做主  比尔  无论怎样我都支持你
It's your call, Bill. I'll back you either way.
我的人在外边损失惨重
I'm losing a lot of men out there.
我现在就能制止它
I can do something about that right now.
把电话给我
Give me that phone.
给他接通
Patch him through.
喂?  喂  是我  卡维尔
Hello? Hello, it's me, Cavil.
全面撤退!
Stand down, all forces!
所有武力马上停火!
Cease fire immediately!
卡拉狄加  我是热狗
Galactica, Hotdog.
他们正在撤退
They're pulling back.
重复  他们正在撤退!
Repeat, they're pulling back!
所有人…
Everyone,
放下武器
stand down.
我言而有信
I'm as good as my word.
上将  蝮蛇编队着陆  我们损失了四架战机
Admiral, Viper wings aboard. We lost four birds.
突击分队着陆  我们损失了七架猛禽
Assault forces aboard, and we've lost seven Raptors.
他们在干什么?
ROSLIN: What are they doing?
他们每个人都知道复活技术的一部分
Each of them knows part of the secret to resurrection,
他们需要通过水中的数据流互相交流
and they're gonna interact with the data flow in the water
然后...我不知道
and... I don't know.
他们五人之间如何共享信息
It's a lot of complicated technical talk about sharing the information
然后通过某种方式传回殖民地
among the five of them and then transferring
要涉及很多复杂的技术术语
it over to the colonies somehow.
那么  片刻之后
Now, for a moment,
我们将知道彼此的一切
we're going to know everything there is to know about one another.
对此我很期待
I'm looking forward to that.
无疑有些事情...
There are certain things that...
我们都做过
That we've all done, certain things that
一些让他人震惊的事情
people would be shocked to learn about.
喂  我不想催你们
Hey, I don't mean to rush you,
但你们这是让两个文明在等待!
but you are keeping two civilizations waiting!
我们...我们先说好  不管...
Let's just all agree that no matter
我们知道彼此做过什么事...
what we learn about each other,
我们都是赛昂  我们都可能犯错误
we're all Cylons, and we're all capable of making mistakes.
好  好  好  你这是在原谅你不可告人的秘密
Yeah, yeah, yeah, you're forgiven for all your dark secrets.
我们开始吧
Let's do this.
有消息吗?
Any word?
我们开始收到数据了.
We're getting the data now.
看上去是对的
It looks right.
他们正在下载复活枢纽的设计数据
They're downloading the resurrection designs now.
他们中断了下载
They've broken off the download!
他们在耍花招!开火!
It's a trick! Open fire!
妈的!
Frak!
我们得离开这儿!
We've gotta get out of here!
星芭  将船跳离!
Starbuck! Jump the ship!
我没有集合地坐标!
I don't have the rendezvous coordinates!
不管了!
It doesn't matter!
马上带我们跳跃离开这里!  跳跃!
Just jump us out of here now! Jump!
要相信你自己
Just trust yourself.
肯定有办法离开这儿
There must be some kind of way out of here.
我想如果把数字与音符对应...
STARBUCK: I thought that if I assigned numbers to the notes...
如果躺在那儿的是我  那我算什么?
If that's me lying there, then what am I?
我现在注视着你  看到的不是卡拉·色瑞丝
SAM: I look at you now and I don't see Kara Thrace.
我看到一个闪耀神之光芒的天使
I see an angel blazing with the light of God. Angel.
跳跃!
Jump!
你在冒不必要的风险
You're tempting fate.
嗯
Mmm.
我若有我的命运  那也是天数已定
If I have a fate then it is set, and thinking about it
再怎么想也不会让它加速发生
isn't gonna make it happen any faster.
好的  说的有理
Okay. Fair enough.
但是在飞的时候
But flying?
你还想着死亡...
When you're thinking about dying...
那这做事方式也太差劲了
It's a bad way of doing business.
你会开始害怕
You're gonna get scared,
会开始质疑自己的能力
and you're gonna start second-guessing yourself.
我不害怕
I'm not scared.
你说你每次进入驾驶舱的时候
You said that you think about dying
都会想到死亡
every time that you get into a cockpit.
嗯对
Uh-huh.
喂喂?
Well, hello!
是的  但这吓不倒我 李
Yeah, but it doesn't scare me, Lee.
你不会明白的
That's what you don't get.
喔  那么是说...卡拉·色瑞丝 是无畏的武士
What, so it's Kara Thrace, the fearless warrior?
是吗?
Right?
不  我也...知道恐惧
No, I know... I know fear,
我也会害怕
and I get scared, just...
只是...不是害怕死亡
Just not of dying.
那么什么能吓到你?
So then, what does scare you?
嗯
Mmm...
对不起
Sorry.
是被遗忘
Being forgotten.
你还好吗?  我没事
You all right? Yeah, I'm fine.
副长?  长官?
XO. TIGH: Sir.
军情报告  损坏情况
ADAMA: Sitrep. Damage report.
我没事.我没事  去吧
I'm okay, I'm okay, go.
是  长官
Sir.
我们基本上都还在
We're mostly here.
引擎  生命维持系统
The engines, life support.
但她的侧面结构已经全面红色警报
There's red lines through her lateral structural members.
她闪到背了  她不能再跳跃了
She's broke her back. She'll never jump again.
不管身处何处  我们都得要留下来了
Wherever we are is where we're gonna stay.
你把我们带到了哪儿  卡拉?
Where have you taken us, Kara?
很高兴你能加入我们  上将
Glad you could join us, Admiral.
星中尉这个称呼很适合我  长官
Lieutenant Hoshi suits me just fine, sir.
上将星衔想来还是重了点儿
Admiral stars turned out to be a little heavy.
我人生中最快乐的日子就是
Happiest day of my life when I saw
看到猛禽机跳跃出现在集合点
that Raptor jump in at the rendezvous point.
嗯  帮你找着了  上将
Well, there you have it, Admiral.
我们在这个星球可以找到的
The most advanced civilization
最高级文明
we could locate on this planet.
我没看到他们有相互说话
I can't see them talking to each other, sir.
所以  要么他们的交流方式不一样  要么他们还没语言
Either they communicate a different way, or they're pre-verbal.
根据他们所用工具的外观
Judging by the look of their tools,
退一步说  工具是未发展的
which are rudimentary, to say the least,
我认为我们发现了原始的仪式化的部落社会
I'd suggest that we found an early, ritualistic tribal society.
他们会埋葬死者
They bury their dead.
我在几公里远的地方遇到一座坟墓  然后做了些测试
I came across a grave a couple of clicks back and ran some tests.
他们的DNA与我们的可以兼容
Their DNA is compatible with ours.
就是说我们可以与他们繁衍后代
Meaning we can breed with them?
你脑子里就一件事  博士
You got a one-track mind, Doc.
什么?  听着  我说的实际上是人类的生存繁衍
What? Listen, I'm talking about the survival of the human race, actually,
并不是跟当地人搞什么大联欢
not some get-together with the natives.
而且你也没有幽默感
You also have no sense of humor.
没错
Right.
没错  我很抱歉
Right, I'm sorry.
那怎么可能?
ADAMA: How is that possible?
人类在百万光年以外的星球上
Human beings naturally evolved on a planet
自然进化
one million light years away.
不可能的概率是...
The odds against that are...
天文数字级  是的
Astronomical, yeah.
可能会有人说这是神在背后操纵
One might even say there was a divine hand at work.
不管是谁的责任  我们已经在这儿了
Well, whoever's responsible, we're here,
这里就是我们的归宿...
and here's where we're gonna stay,
和我们的新家人
with our new families.
我建议我们清理这一片  直到这个山脊
My vote is that we clear everything back to this ridge.
沿着河畔  取水很便利
There's easy access to the water down by the river.
实际上  这一大片地方都适合耕种
In fact, the whole area is ripe for cultivation.
我们应该可以在一两天内
HOSHI: We should be able to lay out the preliminary lines for a city
划定城市的大概轮廓
within a day or two.
不
No.
不要城市
No city.
至少现在不要
Not this time.
那你建议我们做什么呢?
What do you propose we do?
我们要打破循环
APOLLO: We break the cycle.
我们抛掉一切然后从头再来
We leave it all behind and start over.
你正在谈论的可是超过38000人
You're talking about a little over
整个人类种族
38,000 people, the entire human race,
除了身上的衣服和一些必需品之外一无所有
with nothing but the clothes on their backs and some provisions.
并不是整个人类种族
It's not the entire human race.
这里本来就有人了
There are people already here.
部落
Tribal.
甚至没有语言
Without language, even.
但是我们可以给他们啊
Well, we can give them that.
我的意思是 我们可以把
I mean, we can give them the...
自己最好的部分给他们
The best part of ourselves.
而不是给他们行李  不是舰船
And not the baggage, not the ships,
装备  技术  武器
the equipment, the technology, the weapons.
如果有一件事是我们应该吸取教训的  那就是…
If there's one thing that we should have learned it's that...
你知道的  我们的脑力发展总是超过我们的内心
You know, our brains have always outraced our hearts.
我们的科技冲锋在前  我们的灵魂落在后面
Our science charges ahead, our souls lag behind.
让我们重新开始
Let's start anew.
我们将把平民降落在星球上
ADAMA: We'll land civilians at various points
多个地点
around the planet.
我们的目的是
Our objective will be to spread
尽可能的分散人群
the people out as much as possible
给他们最大的生存可能
to give them the best possibility of survival.
物资会在聚居地之间平均分配
Supplies will be evenly distributed throughout the camps,
地点会被记录在案然后告诉所有人
and locations will be documented and given to everyone.
我不得不说  我对大家对这个提案如此接纳感到吃惊
I have to say, I'm shocked at how amenable everyone is to this notion.
我原以为  放弃我们仅存的这点物质享受的主意
I would have thought there'd be a general uprising at the idea
会引到普遍的反对
of losing whatever little creature comforts we had left.
不要低估大家对从头再来的渴望  拉姆金先生
Don't underestimate the desire for a clean slate, Mr. Lampkin.
你们决定好了吗?
Have you made a decision?
六号  八号  和二号们已经决定留下来
The Sixes, the Eights, and the Twos have decided to stay.
看看我们在被上帝召走之前
See how we can contribute to a world
能为世界贡献点什么
before we pass into God's hands.
我们会把基地之星交给赛昂武士
We'll give the Baseship to the Centurions,
让他们去寻找他们自己的归宿
let them find their own destiny.
我想他们已经赢得了自由
I think they've earned their freedom.
要是他们再次自我进化
And what if they evolve again on their own
几百年后决定回来消灭我们怎么办?
and decide to come back in a few hundred years and wipe us out?
这是有点冒险
It's a risk,
但是我想给他们自由应该
but I think setting them free may be enough
足以打破暴力的循环
to break the cycle of violence.
这个险值得冒
ADAMA: Then it's a risk worth taking.
我同意  他们自己赢得的
And I agree. They've earned it.
一旦平民们都离舰了
Now, once the civilians have been offloaded,
舰队将会离开轨道
the Fleet will leave the orbit
并跟卡拉狄加会合
and rendezvous with Galactica.
舰队的航线将会
The course of the Fleet will be plotted
事先在导航电脑中设置好
into the nav computer ahead of time,
但是实际的引航将由安德斯先生完成
but the actual piloting will be done by Mr. Anders.
他将引导整个舰队直接驶入太阳
He'll guide the entire Fleet directly into the sun.
我爱你
I love you.
再见…
Goodbye,
山姆
Sam.
我会在另一边跟你相会
I'll see you on the other side.
你的名字叫威廉·阿达玛?
MAN: Is your name William Adama?
是的
Yes.
你是一名殖民舰队的军官吗?
Are you an officer in the Colonial Fleet?
是的
Yes.
你是赛昂人吗?
Are you a Cylon?
对不起  比尔  我们还是要通过测试来保证可靠
I'm sorry, Bill. We're still establishing tests for the control.
我需要甄别"是"和"不是"
I need verifiable yeses and nos.
不.我不是赛昂
No, I'm not a Cylon.
你曾经贪污过公款吗?
Have you ever stolen money from a cash drawer?
你曾经贪污过...
Have you ever stolen money...
少来废话
Enough of this crap.
马上把这东西从我身上拿开  没什么工作值得这样
Take this thing off of me right now. No job is worth this,
不管薪水有多高
no matter how fat the paycheck is.
我宁愿让我剩下的职业生涯  剩下的日子
I'd rather spend the rest of my career, or what's left of it,
在一艘老破船上度过
in a broken-down old ship,
也不要让别人坐在这质疑我的话
than have someone sit here and question my word.
力求完美
SAM: Perfection.
那才是重要的
That's what it's about.
那些瞬间...
It's those moments
当你能感觉到万物的完美...
when you can feel the perfection of creation,
那物理之完美  知道不  数学的奇妙
the beauty of physics, you know, the wonder of mathematics
作用和反作用的高涨热情
and the elation of action and reaction,
而那就是
and that is the kind of perfection
我所要达到的完美
that I want to be connected to.
你确定这就是你想要的  格伦?
You're sure this is what you want, Galen?
是的  我很肯定
Yeah, I'm sure.
只是厌倦了人群  不管是人类还是赛昂
I'm just tired of people, humans, Cylons, whatever.
明天最后一架飞出的猛禽机会把我送到
Last Raptor out tomorrow is gonna drop me off on this island that I found
我在北边大陆找到的一个岛上
off one of the northern continents.
那很冷  在高地上
It's cold. It's up in the highlands.
那儿没人
There's no people.
祝你好远
Good luck.
不管怎样  要是
For what it's worth, if what happened
发生在凯莉身上的事发生到艾伦身上
to Cally had happened to Ellen,
我他妈的也会那么做的
then I'd have done the same frakking thing.
嗯
Hmm.
嘿!
Hey!
啊!
Ah!
我还以为比尔会来
I thought Bill was coming.
他在嘘嘘
He's taking a leak.
哦  很好
Oh, nice.
嘿  帮我叫一杯酒  宝贝  喝个不停
Hey, order me a drink, honey, and keep them coming.
今晚我们好好庆祝庆祝你的退休
Tonight we are celebrating your retirement
和那些即将和我老公一起度过的日子
and all the time I'm about to get to spend with my husband.
你觉得那很好吗?
Are you good with that?
索尔!  我一直想要的就是和你一起
Saul! All I've ever wanted was to be with you.
不只是周末时间或者是两星期的年假
Not just weekend liberties or a two weeks' leave a year.
我说的是全部时间
I mean full-time.
你和我  一起住在屋子里  或者帐篷…
You and me, together in a house, in a tent,
就算在街头无家可归
homeless and on the street.
能在一起就行
Just be together.
嗯
Mmm-hmm.
不好意思
Excuse me.
啊!
Ah!
别撒我身上!
Oh! Don't drop me!
为我们干杯!
To us!
嗯
BOTH: Mmm!
耶!
Yeah!
它们可真多
There are so many.
等等  我要...
Wait, I wanna...
看清楚点
See more detail.
真是...
It's
一个非常美丽的世界
a very beautiful world.
它有名字吗?
Does it have a name?
地球
Earth.
这不是地球
It's not Earth.
地球是个梦想
Earth is a dream.
这个梦想我们追逐了好长的时间
One we've been chasing for a long time.
我们应得的  这就是地球
We've earned it. This is Earth.
那好吧
Okay then.
地球
Earth.
真好
It's fine.
我...我呼吸有点困难
I'm having trouble breathing.
想不想过去好好看看它们?
Would you like to get a better look at them?
嗯  我很...很想
Yes, I'd love it.
我想的.什么意思?
What... What do you mean?
等着  什么?干嘛?
Watch. What? Why?
你想做什么?
What are you doing?
看我的
Watch me.
你想做什么?  手抱紧我
What are you doing? Put your arm around me.
好吗?
Can you?
爸?
Dad?
我得抓紧时间了  儿子
I don't have much time, Son.
我明白
I understand.
你听到了什么  星芭?
What do you hear, Starbuck?
只听到雨声
Nothing but the rain.
带上你的枪  把猫带回来
Grab your gun and bring in the cat.
你该走了
You should go.
知道么  我对我父亲最早的记忆就是
You know, my very earliest memory of my father
他乘飞船飞走了
was him flying away on a big plane
而我就在想他什么时候会回来
and wondering when he was coming back.
这次他不会回来了
He's not coming back this time.
是的  他不会了
No, he's not.
我也不会了
Neither am I.
你要去哪里?
Where are you going?
我不知道
I don't know.
我只知道我的事已经做完
I just know that I am done here.
我完成了我的旅程
I've completed my journey,
现在感觉也挺好
and it feels good.
你和我...
You and I,
就这里
right here,
就现在
right now.
在桌子上?
On the table?
谅你不敢
I dare you.
我打赌你不敢
I double-dog dare you.
打赌我不敢?
Double-dog dare?
喔...我打赌
I double-dog dare you.
嗯
Hmm.
好吧
All right.
哦哟
Oops!
有东西摔坏了
Something's broken.
我想我最好  呃  该走了
I guess I better get going.
嗯...是的
Yeah.
很高兴见到你...
It was nice to meet you,
李·阿达玛
Lee Adama.
我也是  卡拉·瑟瑞丝
Likewise, Kara Thrace.
那么你呢?
So what about you?
你打算做什么?
What are you gonna do?
今天是你新生活的第一天  李
Today is the first day of the rest of your life, Lee.
嗯
Well,
我一直都想着  这一切都结束后  我就会
I always thought when this was all done I would
放手不管
kick back,
放松放松
relax,
像个普通人一样
spend the rest of my days doing
来打发自己剩下的日子
the absolute minimum humanly possible.
那现在你已经来到这儿了?
And now that you're here?
我想去探险!
I want to explore!
我想要爬上高山
I wanna climb the mountains.
我想要越过大洋  我想要…
I wanna cross the oceans. I wanna...
天啊  真不敢相信我会这样说
Gods, I can't believe I'm saying this.
这些听起去都挺累人的  我肯定是疯...
It sounds so exhausting. I must be crazy...
再见  卡拉
Goodbye, Kara.
你不会被遗忘的
You won't be forgotten.
劳拉  你还好吗?
SEAN: Laura? You okay?
嗨  嗨
Hi. Hi.
肖恩  今晚是个愉快的夜晚
Sean, it's been a lovely evening.
真的很开心
Really lovely.
不过什么？
But what?
不过我想我们不能再次这样了
But I'm afraid we won't be doing this again.
是不是我...  不
Did I... No.
不  不  不是你 你很好
No, no, not you. No, you're wonderful.
那就再...  不
Come on, then... No.
你请自己出去吧
You can show yourself out.
很抱歉
I'm sorry.
哇
Wow.
好吧
Okay.
你好  我是劳拉·罗丝琳
Hello, this is Laura Roslin.
我想留个讯息给埃达市长
I'd like you to give a message to Mayor Adar.
告诉他  我会...
Tell him that I will
加入他的总统竞选阵营
be joining his campaign.
谢谢
Thank you.
自始至终直到最后
All the way to the end.
不管怎样
No matter what.
自始至终直到最后
All the way to the end.
这么多的…
So much
生命
life.
真是个富饶的大陆
It's a rich continent.
比十二个殖民地的野生动植物加起来都要多
More wildlife than all the 12 Colonies put together.
找个安静点的地方来建那幢小木屋
Just looking for a quiet little place for that cabin.
或者花园
Maybe a garden.
我没什么园艺才能
I don't have much of a green thumb,
所以希望最好你懂些
so I hope that you do...
就在那儿
Right there.
我打算在那里建房子  劳拉
I'm gonna build it right there, Laura.
这个星球上有好多猎物
HELO: Lot of game on this planet.
我是个很不错的猎人  你知道吗?
I'm a pretty good hunter, you know?
是  没错
ATHENA: Yeah, right.
你在笑什么呢?  怎么了?
What are you laughing at? What?
卡布里卡上的那个兔子
That buck on Caprica.
哦  好了  快别这样  这样说不公平
Okay, come on, now. That's not fair.
嘿  别听你妈妈说的  你老爸我可是个很厉害的猎人
Hey, don't you listen to Mommy. Daddy is a great hunter.
不  让妈妈来教你怎么打猎
No, Mommy's gonna teach you how to hunt.
不  不  不  不  真正的打猎
No, no, no, no. Real hunting.
不  对
No. Yeah.
我还要教你怎么建房子  怎么去种庄稼
And I'm gonna teach you how to build a house and how to plant crops.
好吧  可能妈妈会教你那些
Okay, maybe Mommy will teach you that,
但爸爸会教你怎么打猎
but Daddy's gonna teach you how to hunt.
赫拉
ATHENA: Hera!
赫拉...
Hera.
她会没事的吧?
Will she be all right?
她活下来了.多亏了你们
She survived thanks to you.
你们两
Both of you.
就这样了?
And that's it?
这就是神要我们做的?
That's all God wants of us?
神的计划永远不会结束
God's plan is never complete.
好极了
Great.
不过我有把握这么说
But I think it's safe to say
从今以后  你们的生活 不会再那么多事了
that from now on, your lives will be less
我一直在想
eventful.
毕竟我还是可以帮你办点事的
I've been thinking I may be able to help you out after all,
就是之前你要我帮忙的那件事
about that thing you were asking about before,
进入防御主机里偷看资料
getting a peek into the defense mainframe.
对我老板来说很重要
That would mean a lot to my employers.
不  我做这件事不是为你老板
Yeah, well, I'm not doing it for your employers.
我是为你做的  这让你有什么感觉?
I'm doing it for you. How would it make you feel?
我会非常感激你的
I'd be very grateful.
希望经得住考验
We'll put that to the test.
因为如果一旦有人发觉  我可是会掉脑袋的
Because if anyone finds out, I could get my head cut off.
所以我希望你能谨慎
So I'll count on your discretion.
做这件事是因为爱
The things men do for love.
爱?
Love?
盖尤斯?
Gaius!
是  那么...
Yeah, well...
你知道我的意思  不是吗?
You know what I mean, don't you?
在那边  那两个山峰之间
Over there, between those two peaks,
我看到有很适合耕种的地形
I saw some terrain that looked good for cultivation.
耕种?
Cultivation?
是的
Yes.
你知道  我会干农活
You know, I know about farming.
嗨
Hey.
我知道
I know.
我知道你会
I know you do.
今天我设计好了小木屋
ADAMA: I laid out the cabin today.
面朝东  风景好
It's gonna have an easterly view.
你应该看看这里的阳光
You should see the light that we get here.
当太阳从那些山后面升起来
When the sun comes from behind those mountains,
简直就像是在天堂
it's almost heavenly.
这让我想起了你
It reminds me of you.
本周在位于华盛顿的
NO. 6: "At a scientific conference this week
史密森学会的一次科学会议上
"at the Smithsonian Institution in Washington,
发表了一个令人震惊的声明
"the startling announcement was made
考古学家们相信  他们已经发现的
"that archeologists believe they have found
一具年轻女性的化石遗骸
"fossilized remains of a young woman
极有可能是线粒体夏娃
"who may actually be Mitochondrial Eve.
线粒体夏娃是科学家给
"Mitochondrial Eve is the name scientists have given
目前生活在地球上的所有人类的
"to the most recent common ancestor
最近的共同祖先所起的名字
"for all human beings now living on Earth.
她的居住地位于现在的坦桑尼亚
"She lived in what is now Tanzania,
在150000多年以前
"over 150,000 years ago."
和她的赛昂母亲
Along with her Cylon mother
和人类爸爸一起
and human father.
商业主义  道德堕落  滥用科技
Commercialism, decadence, technology run amok.
让你想起什么没有?
Remind you of anything?
随你挑
Take your pick.
科波  地球  我说的是之前那个真的地球
Kobol, Earth, the real Earth, before this one.
陷落之前的卡布里卡
Caprica before the fall.
这一切都曾发生过
All of this has happened before.
但是问题还在
But the question remains.
这一切真的得要再次发生吗?
Does all of this have to happen again?
这次  我赌不会
This time, I bet no.
知道吗  我从不认为你是个乐天派
You know, I've never known you to play the optimist.
为什么改变主意?
Why the change of heart?
数学上的  统计平均律
Mathematics, law of averages.
让一个复杂系统反复运转足够长的时间
Let a complex system repeat itself long enough,
最终令人惊讶的事情可能会发生
eventually something surprising might occur.
这也是神的计划的一部分
That, too, is in God's plan.
你知道它不喜欢那名字
You know it doesn't like that name.
愚蠢的我
Silly me.
愚蠢  愚蠢的我
Silly, silly me.